(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-pro-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
始まりはきっと
It surely began with
一つの願い
a single wish.
それを抱いて私は
Embracing that,
生まれた
I was born.
孤独な夜空
In the lonely night sky,
震える指先で
with trembling fingertips,
点と点を繋げよう
let's connect the dots.
Wow wow...
一次元では
In the first dimension,
寂しすぎるから
it's too lonely, so
私たちは
we sought
広がりを求めた
to expand.
点は線となり
Points became lines,
線は立体となり
lines became 3D shapes,
そこに距離が生まれたけれど
but distance was born there.
三次元では
In the third dimension,
ちょっと
it's a little
遠すぎるから
too far apart, so
私たちは
we sought
平面に求めた
a flat plane.
点は線となり
Points became lines,
線は星座となり
lines became constellations,
この夜空を繋ぐよ
connecting this night sky.
自分らしく
A place where I can
居られる場所を
be myself...
気付けばずっと
I realized I had always
探していた
been searching for it.
煌めく星を
Tracing the twinkling stars
辿り鉄の上
on this railway,
この未開拓を
making this frontier
目印に
my landmark.
雨のち君がいつも
You were always there
そこにいたから
after the rain,
嬉しくて続けたんだ
so I happily kept going
今日まで
until today.
忘れないでね
Please don't forget,
僕らの星座は
our constellation was
君がいたから生まれた
born because you were here.
Wow wow...
例え君がいつの
Even if you live
時を生きては
in any era,
何かを好きになる気持ち
please cherish and keep singing
大切に歌い続けてね
the feeling of falling in love with something.
僕らの星座は
Our constellation
君がいるから生まれ
is born because you are here,
夜空に輝き
shining in the night sky,
明日へと繋がる
connecting to tomorrow.
Wow wow...
未来を目指すよ
We'll aim for the future.
共に行こう
Let's go together.
これは僕らのキセキ、
This is our miracle.
僕とキミと、大切なあの子の
Of me, you, and that precious girl.
この王国で過ごす、かけがえのない日々を綴る
Weaving the irreplaceable days spent in this kingdom,
僕たちの物語
this is our story.
僕の居る意味はどこにあるの？
Where is the meaning of my existence?
誰かに必要とされたかった
I wanted to be needed by someone.
夢や希望も捨てきれないけど
I can't fully give up on dreams and hopes, but
なんとなく今を生きている
I'm just somehow living in the now.
ああ どれだけ叫んでも
Ah, no matter how much I scream,
この声は君には届かない
this voice won't reach you.
ああ どれだけ叫んでも
Ah, no matter how much I scream,
この声は君には届かない
this voice won't reach you.
金木犀の匂いがした
I smelled the fragrant olive.
明日のことも忘れたくなった
I wanted to forget about tomorrow too.
いっそ逃げてしまおうかな
Maybe I should just run away.
僕は悲劇の主人公だ
I am the protagonist of a tragedy.
優しいヒトで居たいな
I want to be a kind person.
でもそんな思いも偽善だ
But even that thought is hypocrisy.
誰も幸せにできないの
I can't make anyone happy.
都合良いね、涙が出るの
How convenient, tears are falling.
どれだけ歌っても
No matter how much I sing,
この声は君には届かない
this voice will not reach you.
ああ どれだけ歌っても
Ah, no matter how much I sing,
この声は君には届かない
this voice will not reach you.
ああ 息が苦しくなる
Ah, it becomes hard to breathe.
この歌もいつしか終わりが来る
This song too will eventually come to an end.
ああ 息が苦しくなる
Ah, it becomes hard to breathe.
この地球もいつかは終わりが来る
This planet too will eventually come to an end.
金木犀の匂いをまた
The scent of osmanthus again...
思い出した
...I remembered.
気付けば駆け出していた
Before I knew it, I was running,
揺れ動く心のままに
following my wavering heart.
遠ざかる白い壁
The receding white walls,
一度も振り返らずに
without looking back even once.
命が消え逝く季節の
Of the season when life fades away,
胸を刺す気配の中で
in the presence that pierces my chest.
迫りくる暗い闇
The approaching dark darkness,
二度と明けないような気がして
feeling like it will never dawn again.
転がり落ちそうな心
My heart that seems about to roll down,
必死に抱き止めていた
I was desperately holding it back.
星空へと続く長い坂道は
The long slope leading to the starry sky...
永遠にも思えたから
...seemed like it would last forever.
咲く花や散りぬるを
Blooming flowers and falling ones,
神代の時より繰り返す
repeating since the age of gods.
私はそれを美しいとは
I have never thought...
思ったことがない
...that that is beautiful.
絶えず久方の春の陽を
Constantly, the eternal spring sunlight,
仮初の影が奪い合う
temporary shadows snatch from each other.
その営みを美しいとは
I have never thought...
思ったことがない
...that that cycle is beautiful.
諦めながら生きてた
I lived while giving up,
何も望まないように
trying not to wish for anything,
それでも
but still...
手放せなかった
...I couldn't let go.
最後の願いを
Clutching the last wish,
握りしめて駆け上がる
I run up the slope.
我武者羅に生きるお前が笑われて
You, living recklessly, are laughed at,
楽に生きる奴が得をする世界で
in a world where those who live easily gain.
我だけはお前のことを笑わない
Only I will not laugh at you!
皆が指差し笑おうとも我は笑わない
Even if everyone points and laughs, I will not laugh!
ああ 人は滅んでゆく ほころんでゆく
Ah, people perish, they come apart.
才を妬み合い 富を奪い合い
Envying talent, stealing wealth.
ああ 人は滅んでゆく ほころんでゆく
Ah, people perish, they come apart.
その果てに見えた海は
The sea seen at the end of that...
地獄だろうか それとも地獄だろうか
is it hell? Or is it hell?
我武者羅に生きるお前が笑われて
You, living recklessly, are laughed at,
楽に生きる奴が得をする世界で
in a world where those who live easily gain.
我だけはお前のことを笑わない
Only I will not laugh at you!
皆が指差し笑おうとも我は笑わない！
Even if everyone points and laughs, I won't laugh!
我は笑わない
I won't laugh.
正直に生きるお前が貶されて
You, who live honestly, are disparaged,
嘘で生きる奴らが徳となる世界で
In a world where those who live by lies profit,
我だけはお前の腕を離さない！
I alone will not let go of your arm!
時を刻み忘れようとも我は離さない
Even if time forgets to tick, I won't let go.
我は離さない！
I won't let go!
我は忘れない！
I won't forget!
身を粉にして働いても
Even if you work yourself to the bone,
感謝されないことも... (シバシバ)
And aren't thanked for it... (often).
自己犠牲を受け入れても
Even if you accept self-sacrifice,
限界がもうやってくるから
Your limit is already approaching,
自分を大事に愛せばいい
So you should just cherish and love yourself.
それは他人を愛すること
That is what it truly means to love others.
嗚呼 人は病んでゆく
Ah, people fall into illness,
損なってゆく
Losing themselves,
塵に戻ってゆく
Returning to dust.
嗚呼 人は老いてゆく
Ah, people grow old,
救われてゆく
Being saved.
君に逢えたから...
Because I met you...
君を愛したから...
Because I loved you...
君が闘うなら...
If you fight...
僕も闘うから...
I will fight too...
我武者羅に生きるお前が笑われて
You, living earnestly, are laughed at,
楽に生きる奴らが徳をする世界で
In a world where those who live easy lives profit,
我だけはお前のことを笑わない！
I alone will not laugh at you!
皆が指差し笑おうとも我は笑わない！
Even if everyone points and laughs, I won't laugh!
正直に生きるお前が貶されて
You, who live honestly, are disparaged,
嘘で生きる奴らが徳となる世界で
In a world where those who live by lies profit,
我だけはお前の腕を離さない！
I alone will not let go of your arm!
時を刻み忘れようとも我は離さない
Even if time forgets to tick, I won't let go.
我は離さない！
I won't let go!
我は忘れない！
I won't forget!
それじゃあ今夜は、この王国のお話をしていこう。
Well then, tonight let's talk about this kingdom.
嘘か真か、
Truth or lie,
ここに記されている本は内容がコロコロと変わってしまう、不思議な本でね
the book recorded here is a mysterious one whose contents change constantly.
さて、今回はどんなお話になっているかな。
Now, I wonder what kind of story it has become this time.
これはあるサーカスの団が王国へ訪れ、
This is a story about a circus troupe visiting a kingdom,
まだ未熟な座長さんが、綺羅びやかなステージに包まれたお話
and an immature ringmaster enveloped by a glittering stage.
あぁ...これが私が望んだ夢のエンディング！
Ah... this is the dream ending I wished for!
さあ、今日も始まりました〜！
Come on, it's started again today!
煌びやか、享楽のパレード
A glittering, hedonistic parade.
常識もここじゃ無関係
Common sense is irrelevant here.
踊れ歌え騒げ全て忘れて
Dance, sing, make noise, forget everything!
細かいことは置いといて
Put the little details aside,
とりあえず身を任せてみな
just give yourself over to it for now.
幸福を少し分けるような
Like sharing a little bit of happiness...
饗宴 Show Time!
A feast, Show Time!
積もりゆく不安や後悔
Piling anxiety and regrets,
今だけはちょっと目を背けて
turn your eyes away just for now.
そのままじゃ楽しめないじゃん
You can't enjoy it like that.
この場だけは何もかもを忘れて！
Forget absolutely everything just for this moment!
幾千の価値観全部
All the thousands of values,
引っ括め楽しませてあげる
I'll bundle them up and entertain you.
百鬼夜行もビックリの
Surprising even the Night Parade of One Hundred Demons,
隊を成している
forming a corps.
怪奇模した喜劇が幕開け
A comedy mimicking the bizarre opens its curtains.
一目見ればたちまち虜に！
One look and you'll be instantly captivated!
どんな愛も受け入れてくれる
It accepts any kind of love.
ここだけはあなたの理想郷
This place alone is your utopia.
もう間もなく主役の登場、
The main act will appear very soon,
一時でも目を離さないで！
don't take your eyes off even for a moment!
眩しいほどのステージが始まる
A dazzling stage is about to begin.
想像して
Imagine,
華々しいスポットライトの中
in the brilliant spotlight,
目を奪うような妙技の数々
numerous feats that steal your eyes.
この空間が世界で一番
This space is the number one in the world,
娯楽の名に相応しいんだ！
worthy of the name of entertainment!
割れんばかりの歓声と拍手で
With cheers and applause that could crack the air,
ショーは回っていく
the show goes on.
まあ、これはあくまで理想の話なんですが
Well, this is just an ideal story, though.
さて今日も始めましょうか…
Well then, shall we begin today as well?
あ〜、またやっちゃった〜
Ah, I did it again~
実際はご覧の通り、まだまだ未熟な見習いなんです
As you can see, I'm actually still an inexperienced apprentice.
先人に憧れ持って、私もと飛び込んだものの
Admiring my predecessors, I jumped in too, but...
現実はそんな簡単に、上手くいかないなあ…
Reality isn't that simple, things don't go that smoothly...
もう一回！怪奇模した喜劇が幕開け
One more time! The curtain rises on a comedy mimicking the bizarre.
一目見ればたちまち虜に
One look and you'll be instantly captivated.
え？既にそれさっき見た？
Eh? You already saw that just now?
なら、飽き性なあなたにも朗報
Then, good news for you who gets bored easily.
ちょっと前の模倣をするだけ
I'll just imitate what happened a moment ago.
繰り返しじゃつまらない！
Repetition is boring!
だから、ここから先は趣向を変えてみよう！
So, let's change things up from here on out!
ドタバタなサーカスの行方は
Where this slapstick circus is headed...
誰にも自分すらも分からない
No one knows, not even me.
私を選んだ君だけでも楽しんでってよ〜〜〜損させないから
At least you who chose me, enjoy yourself! I won't let you down.
いつの日か皆と楽しめるショーがしたいんだよな〜！
Someday I want to put on a show that everyone can enjoy!
だからこそ、こんなとこで挫けるわけとかな〜い！
That's why there's no way I can give up here!
言葉なんかじゃ言い表せない
Words aren't enough to express it,
あの感動を私もいつか…
that excitement, someday I too...
とても偉大なこのステージに
Whether I'm worthy of this great stage,
見合っているか分かんないけれど
I don't know yet, but...
観客全て、私の色で
I'll dye the entire audience in my color,
染め尽くしてやろう
I'll paint them completely.
手始めに、今、眼の前の君たちからいくよ〜〜〜！！！
For starters, I'm coming for you guys right in front of me now!
創造しよう
Let's create it,
華々しいスポットライトの中
amidst the brilliant spotlight.
目を奪うような妙技の数々
A myriad of eye-catching feats.
この空間が世界で一番
This space is the one most worthy
“娯楽”の名に相応しいんだ！
of the name 'Entertainment' in the whole world!
割れんばかりの歓声と拍手で
With earth-shattering cheers and applause,
ショーが終わっていく
the show comes to an end.
ああ…これが私が望んだ夢のエンディング
Ah... this is the dream ending I wished for.
これは 花の国のお姫様が
This is the story of when a princess from the Flower Kingdom
この王国へいらっしゃった時のお話
came to visit this kingdom.
まだみんな彼女の事を知らない頃だったので
Since it was back when no one knew her yet,
国民の大半は、アホの子なんて言ってたけど
most of the citizens called her a 'foolish child', but...
とっても心優しくそして気さくで
She was a very kind-hearted, friendly,
頼りになるお姫様だったんだよ
and reliable princess.
なんてったって、みこはお姫様なんだから！
After all, Miko is a princess!
女神！聖女！英知聡明！慈愛！博愛！
Goddess! Saint! Wise and Intelligent! Affection! Charity!
ですわ！
It is so!
あたしなんてったってお姫様
After all, I am a princess.
この人生におけるヒロイン
The heroine of this life.
ですわー！
It is so!
一生遊んでイージーモード
Playing around my whole life in easy mode,
って思ったら勝手にどうぞ！
if that's what you think, go right ahead!
世間はいつも風向き次第
The world is always changing like the wind.
有象無象ばかりでホント
Truly full of riff-raff everywhere.
人間不信になっちゃう
It makes me lose faith in humanity.
傷ついたのこの世界に
I was hurt by the fact that this world
血も涙もないこと
has no blood or tears.
あれもダメ これもダメ それもダメ どれもダメ
That's no good, this is no good, that's no good, nothing is good.
現実は世知辛い
Reality is tough.
全部改変ですね…
It's all getting rewritten, isn't it...
全部改変ですわー！
It's all getting rewritten!
あたしなんてったってお姫様
After all, I am a princess.
この人生におけるヒロイン
The heroine of this life.
悲しいシナリオも
Even the sad scenarios,
全部全部書き換えちゃうの
I'll rewrite them all, every single one.
だってだって お姫様
Because, because, I'm a princess.
自分の物語くらいは
At least for my own story,
キラキラ楽しまなきゃ
I have to enjoy it sparklingly!
ですわ ですわ ですわ
It is so, it is so, it is so!
今にみてなさい
Just you watch.
運命なんて
Destiny and such,
改変して差し上げますわー！
I shall rewrite it for you!
だれ？だれ？だれだれだれ？
Who? Who? Who, who, who?
裏で糸引いてるのはだれ？
Who is pulling the strings from behind?
操り人形だなんて
Being a marionette,
ごめんだわ まったく
I refuse, honestly.
上品な顔してても
Even with an elegant face,
黒幕はあの人かも
the mastermind might be that person.
まずはあたしが
First, I have to,
強くならなきゃ
become stronger.
未来は変わらない
The future won't change.
自分改革ですわー！
It's a self-reformation!
そうよなんてったってお姫様
That's right, after all I am a princess.
あたしこそ最高権力者
I am the supreme ruler.
生涯のすべての
All of my life's
主導権はこちらにあるわ
initiative lies with me.
だってだって お姫様
Because, because, I'm a princess.
自分で決めたことくらいは
At least what I've decided for myself...
ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
Desuwa! Desuwa! Desuwa!
女神！聖女！叡智聡明！慈愛！博愛！
Goddess! Saint! Wise and Intelligent! Affection! Philanthropy!
ですわ！
Desuwa!
今日は軽くステップする
I'll step lightly today.
運命の歯車が踊り出す
The gears of fate start to dance.
顔を上げたその時
The moment I lifted my face...
ほら世界が恋する
Look, the world falls in love.
あーたしハッピーエンドプリンセス
I am the Happy End Princess!
この人生におけるヒロイン
The heroine of this life.
すったもんだある日々も
Even the days full of trouble and strife,
全部全部
all of it, all of it,
愛してみせるの
I'll show you I can love them!
ハッピーエンドプリンセス
Happy End Princess!
自分の物語くらいは
At least for my own story,
キラキラ楽しまなきゃ
I have to enjoy it sparklingly.
ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
Desuwa! Desuwa! Desuwa!
全力で生き抜かなきゃ
I have to survive with all my might.
ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
Desuwa! Desuwa! Desuwa!
今に見てなさい
Just you watch,
運命なんて
something like fate...
改変して差し上げますわ！
I'll rewrite it for you!
女神！聖女！叡智聡明！慈愛！博愛！
Goddess! Saint! Wise and Intelligent! Affection! Philanthropy!
ですわ！
Desuwa!
王国で一躍有名になった小説の1つじゃないか
Isn't this one of the novels that suddenly became famous in the kingdom?
…ある女学生探偵と推理作家の先生が織りなす楽しい…え？
...The fun story woven by a certain schoolgirl detective and a mystery writer... eh?
いやいやこの事件が実際にあったのかまではわからないよ、
No, no, I don't know if this case actually happened or not,
でも、このシリーズは凄く人気なんですよね
but this series is extremely popular, isn't it?
わかりました！犯人はあなたですね！
I understand! The culprit is you!
開巻劈頭ストーリーライン
At the very beginning, the storyline.
七つ道具は置いちゃえ
Put away the seven tools.
アクロイド殺された
Ackroyd was killed.
探偵がまた一人
Another detective...
姿を消したという
...is said to have disappeared.
綾辻のアリス川
Ayatsuji's Arisugawa.
横溝 掃除は 江戸川か
Yokomizo cleaning is Edogawa?
神田最弱探偵さん
Mr. Kanda, the weakest detective.
こんなんどう？と思う
I think, 'How about this?'
ナンマンダブして
Chanting prayers...
古身の髄
...to the marrow of my old bones.
これ密室なりや
Is this a locked room?
偶と知で会った人
People who met by chance and wit.
愚と痴で別れましょ
Let's part with foolishness and complaints.
謎解きはこれから
The mystery solving starts now.
ララララ
La la la la.
犯人はあなたですね！
The culprit is you!
列車トリック
Train trick,
発火トリック
Ignition trick,
何事件
What case?
推理作家の先生さん
Mr. Mystery Writer.
ウダラパダラ ウダラパダラ
Udara padara Udara padara
言わないで アモーレ
Don't say it, Amore.
頭がこんがらがってきたけれど
My head is getting all tangled up though.
ドットハライ ドットコム
That's all, dot com.
アッチャッチャッチャ パリパリ
Accha ccha ccha pari pari
エブリバデ・ワッコソーバ
Everybody walks all over.
謎はおやつに入りません
Mysteries are not included in snacks.
ドットハライ ドットコム
That's all, dot com.
アッチャッチャッチャ ドンシャリドンシャリ
Accha ccha ccha donshari donshari
エブリバデ
Everybody
アリバイ ないないない
no alibi, no no no.
エトセトラ・ラインヘンバッハ
Etcetera Reichenbach.
カラス鳴き
Crows cawing.
万代 讃 筒井で 五切頂
Bandai praise, Gossetcho in Tsutsui.
オリエント急行
Orient Express.
汽車の窓
Window of the train.
あの怪盗たちが泣くと言う
They say those phantom thieves cry.
弘法クリスティ
Kobo Christie.
二人海原
Two people at sea.
坂口暗号
Sakaguchi Code.
無視したろ
You ignored it, didn't you?
ABCどこ
Where is ABC?
エビスだか
Is it Ebisu?
レモンとちゃんと死刑
Lemon and properly death penalty.
甲が乙を隠す
A hides B.
損者 倒産
Loser, bankruptcy.
三式さん
Mr. Sanshiki.
お疲れさん
Good work.
死者五人やってみな
Try doing five dead people.
死者五人どこ行った
Where did the five dead people go?
謎解きはまだまだ
The mystery solving is still not over.
ダダダダ
Dadadada
そして誰もがいなくなった？
And then everyone disappeared?
増やしになって
Becoming increased.
怪事件
Mysterious case.
お下げ揺らす探偵さん
Pigtails swaying detective.
探偵さん！
Detective!
ロックスベイビー
Locks Baby
ガストンベイビー
Gaston Baby
行かないで アンモ
Don't go, Anmo.
先生の一割は愛
10% of the teacher is love.
ドットハライ ドットコム
That's all, dot com.
アッチャッチャッチャ パリパリ
Accha ccha ccha pari pari
エブリバデ ワッコソーバ
Everybody walks all over.
たまには自分で考えたまえ
Think for yourself once in a while.
ドットハライ ドットコム
That's all, dot com.
アッチャッチャッチャ ドンシャリドンシャリ
Accha ccha ccha donshari donshari
アリバイナイナイナイナイ
Alibi, no, no, no, no!
怪盗連盟の穴にハマる
Falling into the Phantom Thief League's trap,
次々と姿を消していく名探偵達
Great detectives disappear one after another.
そして探偵の居ぬ間に
And while the detectives are away,
人々の心は密室となった
people's hearts became locked rooms.
「でも、それなら...
"But if that's the case...
...どうして私だけが無事だったんでしょうか？」
...why was I the only one left unharmed?"
「その答えは一つしか考えられない」
"There is only one possible answer to that."
「と言うと？」
"Which means?"
「あまりに無能すぎるが故に、
"Because you are so exceedingly incompetent,
君は探偵として勘定にも入れられていなかったのだ！」
you weren't even counted as a detective!"
「ひぃいい！」
"Eek!"
およしになって
Please stop that,
おやめになって
please quit it,
怪事件
mysterious case.
おさげ揺らす探偵さん
The detective with swaying braids.
Knocks Baby
Got on Baby
行かないで And More
Don't go, And More.
先制の
Preemptive,
一万五千連写トリック
15,000 rapid-shot trick.
ハットトリック
Hat trick.
何事件？
What case?
推理作家の
Mystery writer's...
先生！
Sensei!
ウラダラパラダラ ウラダラパラダラ
Uradara paradara, uradara paradara,
言わないで
don't say it!
あーもー
Ah, geez!
ハタマタ こんがらがってきたけど
Or rather, it's getting all tangled up again,
怖いかわいや
scary but cute,
トリック暴いて
expose the trick,
通りゃんせ
pass on through.
小さい2人の子供が約束した
Two small children made a promise.
ずっといっしょに笑っていようの約束
A promise to keep laughing together forever.
今もなお、二人の絆は確かなもので
Even now, their bond remains certain.
友情と愛情が織りなす素敵な物語
A wonderful story woven from friendship and affection.
「あははっ…
"Ahaha...
なんでもないことに、
There are times when...
妙にツボっちゃう時あるよねっ」
...something trivial just hits the funny bone, aren't there?"
あー恋に落ちた繭ら 開花止まらないや
Ah, the cocoons that fell in love, blooming won't stop.
何度もめくって 心をかし
Turning the pages again and again, amusing the heart.
泣いてばっかだったの
I was always crying,
それがどうだ今や
but look at me now,
腹よじれるくらい笑う
laughing until my sides hurt.
ずっと一緒に笑う
Laughing together forever.
君が持ってる白い花に
That white flower you're holding,
あたし見合わない 悲しくなる
I don't suit it, and it makes me sad.
無垢な恋とか
Innocent love,
正しさとか
or righteousness,
誰も教えてくれなかった
no one ever taught me those things.
昨日会ったばっかで
We just met yesterday,
今日もどっか会えたら
but if we could meet again somewhere today,
なんて思う暮らし
living while thinking that...
つつましくないよね
isn't exactly modest, is it?
全部許されたの
Being forgiven for everything,
びっくりしちゃってさ
I was so surprised,
涙あふれてたよ
tears were overflowing.
もう愛になる鼻歌
A humming that turns into love,
透き通った空に
in the clear sky.
手を繋いでった 夢のしるし
We held hands, a sign of a dream.
どんな前世だってさ
No matter what past life it was,
忘れたっていいんだ
it's fine to forget it,
きみと笑えるなら
as long as I can laugh with you.
心が触れるたび 綺麗な音なる
Every time our hearts touch, a beautiful sound rings out.
目と目が合って くすぐったいね
Our eyes meet, and it feels ticklish.
なんでもないこと 妙にツボるね
Trivial things hit our funny bone strangely.
全部教えてくれて ありがとう
Thank you for teaching me everything.
君が持ってる白い花を
If we match that white flower you hold
あたしの紅色と合わせたら
with my crimson color,
霜が解けては雲が行く
the frost melts and the clouds drift away.
もう寒くないよ
It's not cold anymore.
あー恋に落ちた繭ら 開花止まらないや
Ah, the cocoons that fell in love, blooming won't stop.
何度もめくって 心をかし
Turning the pages again and again, amusing the heart.
泣いてばっかだったの
I was always crying,
それがどうだ今や
but look at me now,
腹よじれるくらい笑う
laughing until my sides hurt.
ずっと一緒に笑って
Laughing together forever.
心をかし
Amusing the heart.
ずっと一緒に笑う
Laughing together forever.
最後の日を笑う
Laughing on the final day.
これは、遠い遠い名も知らぬ世界で、
This is, in a far, far unknown world,
死の呪いがかけられた少女のお話
A story of a girl placed under a curse of death.
遠い遠い 時の果て
Far, far away, at the end of time,
そこに住まう人は皆
everyone living there
永遠の命をもつ
possesses eternal life
世界での話
in that world.
赤い実の成る木の下
Under the tree that bears red fruit,
La La Lu La 生まれながらに
La La Lu La, born with it,
死の呪いがかけられた
placed under a curse of death,
少女の話
the story of a girl.
色付いた街外れ
On the outskirts of the colorful town,
蒼く光る湖畔
by the blue glowing lakeside,
赤い実の
red fruit
お菓子屋
pastry shop.
ちょっぴり寒くなった
It's gotten a little cold,
今日は妙に誇らしげ
feeling strangely proud today,
自信作を
my confident creation
売りにゆく
I'm going to sell.
待ってて
Just wait,
今度こそ
this time for sure,
美味しいんだから
it's going to be delicious.
時計塔の見える市
In the market where the clock tower is visible,
驚いた珍しく
surprisingly, unusually,
賑わったね
it was bustling.
La La Lu La Lucky
物憂げな街の隅
In a corner of the melancholic town,
ひとり 赤い実のパイ
all alone, a red fruit pie,
どうですか
how about it?
自信作なの
It's my masterpiece.
そんなのひとつも売れないさ
"We won't buy a single one of those,"
少女を見て蔑む人達
people looking at the girl with scorn.
みんなと何も変わらないのに
Even though she's no different from everyone else,
美味しくできたのに
even though it was made deliciously.
今日も声は届かないので
Today too, since my voice doesn't reach,
まるで透明になったみたいだわ
it's as if I've become transparent.
そうして誰もが知らぬ振りをした
And so everyone pretended not to know,
何故なら少女は呪われているから
because the girl is cursed.
死んだ世界で唯ひとり生きていた
The only one alive in a dead world,
少女の話
the story of a girl.
夜なべでアレンジパイと
Working late at night arranging pies,
にっこりスマイルひっさげ
sporting a big smile,
少女はまだ
the girl still
諦めない
doesn't give up.
時計塔の針も空を指して
The hands of the clock tower point to the sky,
お腹も鳴るそんな時
and her stomach growls, at that time,
ふと後ろから人が少女を押す
Suddenly someone pushes the girl from behind.
甘い籠は落ちる
The sweet basket falls.
お菓子を踏み行く人達
People walk over the sweets,
平気な顔してさ
with unconcerned faces.
惨めに拾い集める
Miserably gathering them up,
ふともうひとりの手が
suddenly another person's hand...
どろどろのパイをモロに口に入れて
Putting the muddy pie straight into their mouth,
「おいしいね」
"It's delicious, isn't it?"
その声で心は溢れた
With that voice, her heart overflowed.
まるで輪郭を描いたみたいだわ
It's as if an outline was drawn.
そうして彼は手を差し出した
And he held out his hand,
何故なら少女に呪われているから
because he is cursed by the girl.
死んだ世界で唯ふたり生きていた
The only two alive in a dead world,
遠い物語
a distant story.
街の人達は哀れむ
The townspeople pity them.
赤い実を食べて呪われた者
The one cursed for eating the red fruit,
永遠に生きられずに死ぬのさ
dying without being able to live forever.
なんて可哀想な話
What a pitiful story.
ふたりは笑う
The two of them laugh,
それでも笑う
even so, they laugh.
La La La とっても素敵な呪いね
La La La, what a wonderful curse.
例え明日死んでも
Even if we die tomorrow,
『今』が確かで大切になるから
because 'now' becomes certain and precious.
もう声は届かないのね
The voice doesn't reach anymore, does it?
まるで透明になったみたいだわ
It's as if we've become transparent.
そうして誰もが知らぬ振りをした
And so everyone pretended not to know,
何故なら世界が呪われているから
because the world is cursed.
『永遠』の呪いは解かれていた
The curse of 'eternity' was broken.
まるでふたりの方が狂ったみたいだろう
It's as if the two of them are the crazy ones, isn't it?
そしていつか笑うように眠る
And someday, I will sleep as if smiling,
何故なら二人は放たれているから
Because the two of us have been set free.
死んだ世界で唯二人が幸せだった
In a dead world, only the two of us were happy.
さて、今日はこれくらいにしておきましょう。
Now then, let's call it a day for now.
そろそろ時間になりましたし。
It is about time, after all.
…え？どこへ向かうのかって？
...Eh? You ask where we are heading?
今日は何の日かご存知ないのですか？
Do you not know what day it is today?
今日は、この王国の地下深くにある冥界でのハロウィンパーティーですよ！
Today is the Halloween Party in the Underworld, deep beneath this kingdom!
死者と生者が楽しむ年に一度のお祭りです。
It is a once-a-year festival where the dead and the living enjoy themselves together.
さあ、一緒に向かいましょう。
Come now, let us head there together.
でも、気を付けて。
But, be careful.
パーティーとはいえ、死者が住まう冥界です、
Even though it is a party, it is the Underworld where the dead reside,
誰かの思念や死者達によって奇妙な事が起こるかもしれません、
Strange things might happen due to someone's lingering thoughts or the dead themselves,
でも、決してそちらに耳を傾けすぎてはいけませんよ。
But, you must never listen too closely to them.
それでは、参りましょう
Well then, let's go.
誰かが言いました
Someone once said,
激しく燃えるものほど
"The more violently something burns,"
煌めく引き換えに
"In exchange for its sparkle,"
その身をすぐ焦がしきると
"It will scorch its body completely in an instant."
数ある燭台に
On the many candlesticks,
お好きな火を灯しましょう
Let's light a fire of your choosing.
期待と裏腹に
Contrary to expectations,
燻ればお生憎様
If it smolders, that is a pity.
ランランランラン
Ran-ran-ran-ran,
右手には錆びた時計
In the right hand, a rusted watch.
ランランランラン
Ran-ran-ran-ran,
左には油の筒
In the left, an oil canister.
ランランランラン
Ran-ran-ran-ran,
絹のドレスを着飾って さあ
Dress up in a silk dress, and come now.
激しく 儚く
Violently, fleetingly...
蒼く燃ゆる花びら
The blue burning petals.
瞬き ゆらめく
Twinkling, flickering...
生を彩り照らせ
Color and illuminate life.
いずれ尽き果てる未来へと
Towards a future that will eventually run out.
ゆりかごの目の前で
In front of the cradle,
遍く飛び交う銃弾
Numerous bullets flying all around.
指だけ動かせば容易くその火は潰える
If you just move a finger, that fire is easily extinguished.
仮初めの情熱で焼け爛れた舌では
With a tongue burnt and festering from a transient passion,
上手に喋ることができないようで
It seems you cannot speak skillfully.
喉元すぎても毒を孕ませて
Even if it passes the throat, it is pregnant with poison,
やがては肺を
Eventually rotting the...
やがては灰を降らせるでしょう
Eventually, it will rain down ash.
揺らぐ死と生の狭間
The wavering gap between life and death.
焼ける心と歌う
Singing with a burning heart.
描いた最愛の終幕を
The beloved finale I envisioned.
激しく 儚く
Violently, fleetingly.
青く燃ゆる花弁
Blue burning petals.
瞬き 揺らめく
Twinkling, flickering.
生を彩り照らせ
Color and illuminate life.
いずれ尽き果てる未来へと
Towards a future that will eventually rot away.
あちらの世界に引きずり込まれないうちに
Before we get dragged into that world,
早く会場へ向かわないといけませんね。
we must hurry to the venue.
気を付けてついてきてくださいね。
Please be careful and follow me.
あまり深入りすると、
If you go too deep,
おっと…
oops...
そうそう、知らない方がきっと懸命ですよ
Yes, yes, it's surely wiser not to know.
なんだかすっごく心地が良いよね
Somehow, it feels really comfortable, doesn't it?
気づけば見知らぬ世界に立っていた
Before I knew it, I was standing in an unknown world.
何処かも分からず
Not knowing where I was,
毎日毎日毎日泣いていた
I cried every single day.
あぁなんて暇もなく
Ah, without even time for that.
Happy Time!
おかしな面々が
Strange faces are...
Happy Time!
おどけて転がるの
joking around and rolling about.
Happy Time!
その馬鹿馬鹿しさに
At that absurdity...
希望も恐怖もなくなった
I lost both hope and fear.
確かそうアタシには
That's right, certainly for me...
為すべき仕事
...there is work to be done.
愛の棲家
A dwelling of love.
パンプキン
Pumpkin
ヘッドギア
Headgear
だけどなんかどーでもいい
But somehow, I don't really care.
さぁ始まった
Now it has begun,
夢の夜だ
a dream-like night.
音楽が響いて
The music echoes,
鳴り止まない
and won't stop ringing.
声を揃えて
Raise your voices together,
叫べ今日は
and shout, today is...
AMAZING HAPPY
HALLOWEEN NIGHT
ジャック悪戯無礼講だ
Jack, tricks, it's a free-for-all.
真面目に生きても割に合わない
Living seriously doesn't pay off.
何でもありさ何故って今日は
Anything goes, after all, today is...
AMAZING HAPPY
HALLOWEEN NIGHT
消えちゃった！消えちゃった！
Disappeared! Disappeared!
(私 は ない だって そう 永遠 に)
(I don't exist, that's right, forever)
消えちゃった！消えちゃった！
Disappeared! Disappeared!
思想 ルール 倫理 関係ない
Ideology, Rules, Ethics, Irrelevant.
AMAZING HAPPY
HALLOWEEN NIGHT
「私はロボットではありません」に
To 'I am not a robot',
無心でチェックし解答するけれど
I check and answer mindlessly, but...
ほ、本当にそうかな？
Is, is that really so?
Happy Life!
とりま音に乗せて
Just ride the sound for now,
Happy Life!
デタラメに踊るの
dancing haphazardly.
Happy Life!
その繰り返しのなか
In that repetition,
懐疑心も失った
I lost even my skepticism.
意志のない様まるで
Looking like I have no will, just like...
ロボトミーした電気羊
a lobotomized electric sheep.
Nightmare
NPC
だけどなんか心地がいい
But somehow, it feels comfortable.
おっと音声が乱れました
Oops, the audio was disturbed.
お気になさらずに皆々様
Please don't mind it, everyone.
そんなお口は縫い合わせて
Sew that mouth shut.
AMAZING HAPPY
HALLOWEEN NIGHT
良い子の口にはチョコとキャンディ
Chocolate and candy for a good child's mouth.
歯に衣着せちゃ噛み合わない
If you mince words, it won't mesh.
気を取り直しみんなでどうぞ
Pull yourself together, everyone go ahead.
AMAZING HAPPY
HALLOWEEN NIGHT
知っちゃった！知っちゃった！
Knew it! Knew it!
(全部 全部 理解した)
(Understood everything, everything)
知っちゃった！知っちゃった！
Knew it! Knew it!
(全部 全部 理解した)
(Understood everything, everything)
知っちゃった！知っちゃった！
Knew it! Knew it!
全部全部理解した
I understood everything, everything.
だから何も見たくねぇわ
That's why I don't want to see anything.
さぁ始まった
Now it has begun,
夢の夜だ
a dream-like night.
音楽が響いて
The music echoes,
鳴り止まない
and won't stop ringing.
声を揃えて
Raise your voices together,
叫べ今日は
and shout, today is...
AMAZING HAPPY
HALLOWEEN NIGHT
ジャック悪戯無礼講だ
Jack, tricks, it's a free-for-all.
真面目に生きても割に合わない
Living seriously doesn't pay off.
何でもありさ何故って今日は
Anything goes, after all, today is...
AMAZING HAPPY
HALLOWEEN NIGHT
泣いちゃった！泣いちゃった！
Cried! Cried!
知らない方がきっと懸命ね
It's surely wiser not to know.
泣いちゃった！泣いちゃった！
Cried! Cried!
このパーティに終わりはない
There is no end to this party.
AMAZING HAPPY
HALLOWEEN NIGHT
トリック・オア・トリート！
Trick or Treat!
お菓子をくれてもイタズラはしちゃうよ！
Even if you give me candy, I'm gonna play a trick on you anyway!
ようこそeveryone 皆の肝揺らすこのSpooky night
Welcome everyone, to this spooky night that'll shake your nerves.
腹の底まで響く kick & bass & hats & trumpet
Kick & bass & hats & trumpet resonating deep in your gut.
ランランとswingin' beat 赤い靴で踊り狂えば
With a bright swingin' beat, if you dance madly in red shoes,
浮世の憂いなど今は忘れられるでしょ
You can forget the sorrows of this fleeting world for now, right?
虐げられちまったじゃ オバケよりも怖い人達
People are scarier than ghosts, having been oppressed by them.
笛吹いちゃってすぐに 1out, 2out, 3... Knock out!!
Blow the whistle and it's instantly 1 out, 2 out, 3... Knock out!!
コンプライアンスも厳しめの世の中でスラ
Even in a world with strict compliance rules,
恐怖のリライト請け負います
We'll undertake a rewrite of your fear.
GIVE ME A CHERRY PIE
それとも may I choke you up?
Or perhaps, may I choke you up?
GIVE ME A FLOWY DRESS
それとも may I stab you to death?
Or perhaps, may I stab you to death?
Poison, rope, rotten cake, knife, scissors... what we play?
choose one... choose one... choose one... choose one...
さぁ選んで？
Come on, choose.
なんちってドッキリ大成功 響くパンパカパンファンファーレで
Just kidding! Huge prank success! With a resounding fan-pa-ka-pan fanfare,
にっこり笑っちゃってハイピース
Smile brightly and say 'Peace'!
あー怖かったななんて 座り込んで涙目で
"Ah, that was so scary," you say, sitting down with teary eyes.
笑う顔みたいな
I want to see that laughing face.
ちっちゃな箱の中の モンスターに怯えるくらいなら
If you're going to be frightened by a monster in a small box,
いつだってここにおいで
Come here anytime.
もっとずっと本能的で 楽しくなれる
You can become much more instinctive and have fun.
恐怖と踊っちゃおうぜ
Let's dance with fear!
相想的に適当キマってカタルシス
Relatively appropriately high on catharsis.
もういっちょ感情ジェットコースターで ご機嫌デトックス
One more time, a good-mood detox on an emotional roller coaster.
Uh oh...
満月が暴く醜悪な本性
The full moon exposes your ugly true nature.
デタラメに杖振り回し Hocus Pocus
Swinging the wand randomly, Hocus Pocus.
劣等感を苗床に育つ妄想を
Do you know the way to pluck the delusions
摘み取る術を知ってるかい
that grow in the seedbed of inferiority?
迷える哀れな子羊たちよ
Oh, lost pitiful lambs...
お菓子が欲しいかい？
Do you want candy?
それとも安らぎが欲しいかい？
Or do you want peace?
永遠に求め続けるの？
Will you keep seeking it forever?
それならばずっと苦しいままだ
If so, you will remain in pain forever.
恐怖からの解放によって
If there is salvation to be found
成し得る救済があるのならば
through liberation from fear...
この目隠しはそのままに
Leave this blindfold as it is.
さあ イタズラ完了
Now, trick complete.
永遠に断ち切れない 呪いの鎖に囚われ
Trapped in a cursed chain that can never be severed,
朽ち果ててしまう前に
Before you completely rot away...
脳みそちょっと弄るだけね あら不思議
Just fiddling with your brain a little, oh how mysterious.
こんなに気持ち良くて 気分爽快
It feels so good and refreshing like this!
なんちってドッキリ大成功 響くパンパカパンファンファーレで
Just kidding! Huge prank success! With a resounding fan-pa-ka-pan fanfare,
にっこり笑っちゃってハイポーズ
Smile brightly and strike a pose!
あー辛かったななんて へたり込んで涙目で
"Ah, that was so tough," you say, collapsing with teary eyes.
笑う顔っていいな
Laughing faces are nice.
もしも死にたくて いいよこんなに頑張ったんだから
If you want to die, it's okay. You've worked so hard, after all.
ためらわずこっちにおいで
Don't hesitate, come over here.
もうずっと本能的で 気持ちいいだけの
Just being instinctive and feeling good forever,
悪夢を見せてあげる
I'll show you a nightmare.
困窮極まってこそ光るカタルシス
Catharsis that shines only when destitution is extreme.
もういっちょ因果全リセットで 魂デトックス
One more time, reset all karma for a soul detox.
Uh oh...
いつかの、あったかもしれない世界の出来事までをも、
Even the events of a world that might have existed someday...
この冥界ではこうして思念として漂っているんだね
Drift here in this underworld as thoughts like this.
あまり深入りしてはいけないよ、こういうのが一番タチが悪い
Don't go too deep. These kinds are the nastiest.
私はただ、あなたを愛していただけ
"I was just loving you."
物言わぬ唇に生気を吹き込んで
Breathing life into silent lips,
今宵「あなた」は甦る、あの頃の姿で。
Tonight "you" will revive, in the form of those days.
白肌の娘が咳をした
The white-skinned girl coughed.
「この身体あなたに捧げるわ」
"I will dedicate this body to you."
白服の医者が囁いた
The doctor in white whispered,
「迎えに行くよ」
"I'm coming to get you."
白肌の娘は朽ち果てた
The white-skinned girl rotted away,
世界の誰にも見捨てられ
abandoned by everyone in the world.
白服の医者は憐れんで
The doctor in white pitied her,
誰も知らない場所で眠らせた
and put her to sleep in a place no one knew.
朽ちてなおまだ
Even as she rots,
美しい顔で
with a face that is still beautiful.
ふたりしかいない霊廟で
In a mausoleum with only the two of them,
医者は恋をした
the doctor fell in love.
それは永遠の恋か。
Is that eternal love?
禁断の行為か。
Or a forbidden act?
また逢いたいと願うだけ。
Just wishing to meet again.
それが罪なのでしょうか。
Is that a sin?
物言わぬ唇に
Into the silent lips,
生気を吹き込んで、
breathing in life,
今宵ふたりは結ばれる。
tonight the two are united.
祝福もされずに。
Without being blessed.
「腐り落ちた眼孔に青いガラスを」
"Blue glass in the rotted eye sockets."
「破れかけた腕に絹の綿を」
"Silk cotton in the torn arms."
「侵された内臓に綿のガーゼを」
"Cotton gauze in the ravaged organs."
「宝石で飾った白いドレスを」
"A white dress decorated with jewels."
朽ちゆくたび
Repairing her
取り繕って、
every time she rots,
恋を謳って
singing of love,
また医者は
the doctor again
手を染め続けた。
continued to stain his hands.
やがて暴かれたのは
Eventually what was revealed
醜い怪物で、
was an ugly monster,
それを造り上げた医者は
and the doctor who created it
弁駁を叫んだ。
shouted a rebuttal.
「これは永遠の恋だ。
"This is eternal love.
彼女の願望だ。」
It is her wish."
「死にゆくと決めたお前らが
"You who decided she would die,
見棄てた女じゃないか」
isn't she the woman you abandoned?"
鳴呼……哀しき花嫁。
Ah... the sorrowful bride.
物言えぬままで、
Remaining unable to speak,
今宵ふたりは裁かれる。
tonight the two are judged.
「彼女を見棄てた
By the justice of the people
人達の正義で。」
who abandoned her.
正しいのはだあれ？
Who is the correct one?
さて ハロウィンパーティーもついにフィナーレ
Well, the Halloween party is finally at its finale.
ここでご参加くださった国民の皆様へ
Here, to all the citizens who participated,
冥界からのお土産品のご紹介です
I'd like to introduce souvenirs from the underworld.
お土産品は全4種類
There are four types of souvenirs in total.
フルセットでご購入いただいた皆様には
For those who purchase the full set,
特典もございます
there is also a special benefit.
ご一緒に詳しく見ていきましょう
Let's take a detailed look together.
まず一つ目
First, number one.
今回の冥界ハロウィンナイトをイメージした
Imaged after this Underworld Halloween Night,
ワイドラバーマットです
is a wide rubber mat.
国王様の横には
Next to the King,
冥界の女王の姿が
is the figure of the Queen of the Underworld.
名をナイラと言うそうです
Her name is Naira, apparently.
冥界のハロウィンを存分に楽しんで欲しいという
With the hope that you fully enjoy the Underworld Halloween,
気持ちを込めた
and putting those feelings into it,
彼女のイメージソングも
her image song also
この後お披露目予定なので
is scheduled to be unveiled after this,
お楽しみに
so please look forward to it.
素敵なイラストはMatcha様に描いていただきました
The wonderful illustration was drawn by Matcha-sama.
二つ目はパスポート風FBKINGDOMシール帳です
The second one is a passport-style FBKINGDOM sticker book.
このシール帳には
In this sticker book,
これから沢山の思い出を記していきたいですね
we want to record many memories from now on, don't we.
王国の軌跡として
As a trace of the kingdom,
国民の皆様も今後集めてみてはいかがでしょうか
how about you citizens also try collecting them in the future?
その一歩として
As the first step,
今回のキービジュアルのステッカーを一枚
one sticker of this key visual
封入しております
is enclosed.
三つ目はSUKONBU FACTORYより
The third one is from SUKONBU FACTORY,
キングフブちゃんぬいぐるみです
King Fubu-chan plushie.
こちらは国王自らデザインをしており
This was designed by the King himself,
とても愛らしいぬいぐるみとなっております
and has become a very adorable plushie.
前回のボリューム1のぬいぐるみをお持ちの方は
Those who have the Volume 1 plushie from last time,
ご一緒に飾ってあげてくださいね
please display them together.
四つ目は王国リボンチャームです
The fourth one is the Kingdom Ribbon Charm.
こちらは秘書である私の胸元のリボンが
This reproduces the ribbon on the chest of me, the secretary.
再現されております
(It is reproduced.)
チャームとなっておりますので...
It functions as a charm, so...
皆様の推し活とやらにぜひご活用ください。
please use it for your so-called 'oshi-katsu' activities.
最後は特典のお知らせです。
Finally, here is the announcement regarding the bonus.
フルセットご購入の方全員に...
For everyone who purchases the full set...
チェキ風ブロマイドカードを1つお付けいたします。
we will include one cheki-style bromide card.
複製サインと、国王からのメッセージもあるそうですよ。
It comes with a duplicated autograph and a message from the King.
数量限定バージョンは直筆サイン入りですので...
The limited quantity version includes a handwritten autograph, so...
皆様お早めに。
everyone, please be quick.
以上、今回のお土産品紹介でした。
That concludes the souvenir introduction for this time.
さて、このあとは...
Now then, after this...
冥界の女王様をイメージした楽曲...
a song imagining the Queen of the Underworld...
『冥界Halloween Night!』のお披露目です。
it's the reveal of 'Meikai Halloween Night!'.
楽しまれた後は...
After you have enjoyed it...
無事、王国へお帰りくださいね。
please return safely to the Kingdom.
それでは。
See you.
Welcome さぁ、踊ろうよ This is Halloween Night
Welcome, come on, let's dance. This is Halloween Night.
冥界を挙げてのParty (Party)
A Party thrown by the whole Underworld (Party)
ルール違反はダメです Warning (Warning)
Rule violations are forbidden, Warning (Warning)
説明は一度きり
I will only explain once
聞き逃せばあの世行き
If you miss it, it's a one-way trip to the afterlife
冗談です
Just kidding.
(いち！) お菓子を回して
(One!) Pass the sweets around
(に！) 仮装して回って
(Two!) Dress up and go around
(さん！) 生者か死者かは隠すこと
(Three!) Hide whether you are living or dead
(よん！) いつだって笑顔で
(Four!) Always with a smile
(ご！) 油断禁物です
(Five!) Never let your guard down
最後の最後はご無事で帰ること
And the very last thing is to return home safely
ひとりきりじゃ つまらないわ
Being all alone is boring
この退屈なお城の玉座で
On the throne of this boring castle
指折りずっと 待ちわびてた
I've been counting the days, waiting eagerly
人恋しいとか？
Lonely for people?
(やだ！) そんなんじゃないってば！
(No way!) I said it's not like that!
Let's 冥界 Halloween Night!
Let's Meikai Halloween Night!
Dancing! Dancing! 闇夜にハッピーなメロディー
Dancing! Dancing! A happy melody in the dark night
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界 Halloween Night!
Rat-tat-ta Rat-tat-ta Meikai Halloween Night!
Swinging! Swinging! ゾッとして愉快なアイロニー
Swinging! Swinging! A shuddering and amusing irony
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 狂宴のショータイム！
Rat-tat-ta Rat-tat-ta Frenzied banquet showtime!
(パ パ パ) 恐ろしや
(Pa pa pa) How scary
(パ パ パ) 恨めしや
(Pa pa pa) How spooky
みんなみんな我さえも忘れてる (オロロロ)
Everyone is forgetting even themselves (Orororo)
(パ パ パ) 美味しそうな
(Pa pa pa) Looks delicious
(パ パ パ) 魂だわ
(Pa pa pa) It's a soul
Welcome さぁ、踊ろうよ This is Halloween Night
Welcome, come on, let's dance. This is Halloween Night.
響く奇怪なチューニング
Resounding bizarre tuning
その不協和音さえもMusic
Even that dissonance is Music
王室のドアが開き
The royal door opens
拍手喝采が起こる
Thunderous applause occurs
快感です
It feels good.
(いち！) 蝋燭を灯して
(One!) Light the candles
(に！) ドレス纏って
(Two!) Put on the dress
(さん！) 女王の私のお出ましです
(Three!) It's the arrival of me, the Queen
(よん！) 手を取り合って
(Four!) Take each other's hands
(ご！) 今日は無礼講です
(Five!) Today, anything goes
私に魅せられちゃったら最後です
If you get charmed by me, it's the end
艶やかなStep くるり舞って One Two
Elegant Step, twirling around One Two
怪奇なこのリズムに揺られて
Swayed by this bizarre rhythm
この楽しさ 癖になるわ
This fun will become a habit
自業自得とか？
You reap what you sow?
(やだ！) 全然足りないってば！
(No!) I said it's not enough at all!
Let's 冥界 Halloween Night!
Let's Meikai Halloween Night!
Dancing! Dancing! 一夜の奇怪なメモリー
Dancing! Dancing! One night's bizarre memory
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界 Halloween Night!
Rat-tat-ta Rat-tat-ta Meikai Halloween Night!
Sweety! Sweety! オブラートに頬張るキャンディー
Sweety! Sweety! Stuffing my cheeks with wafer-wrapped candy
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ もっと頂戴！
Rat-tat-ta Rat-tat-ta Give me more!
泡沫の夢 淡い霧の中溶けて
An ephemeral dream melting into the pale mist
青白い頬を 涙が伝った
Tears streamed down my pale cheeks
この掟は誰の為？
Who is this rule for?
自問自答の...
After questioning myself...
末、禁忌の箱開けたら
...in the end, if I open the forbidden box,
地獄もまた住めば都
Even Hell is home once you live there,
使っちゃおうかな
Maybe I'll use it.
Dancing! Dancing! 闇夜にハッピーなメロディー
Dancing! Dancing! A happy melody in the dark night
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界 Halloween Night!
Rat-tat-ta Rat-tat-ta Meikai Halloween Night!
Swinging! Swinging! ゾッとして愉快なアイロニー
Swinging! Swinging! A shuddering and amusing irony
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 狂宴のショータイム！
Rat-tat-ta Rat-tat-ta Frenzied banquet showtime!
(パ パ パ) 恐ろしや
(Pa pa pa) How scary
(パ パ パ) 恨めしや
(Pa pa pa) How spooky
みんなみんな我さえも忘れてる (オロロロ)
Everyone is forgetting even themselves (Orororo)
(パ パ パ) 美味しそうな
(Pa pa pa) Looks delicious
(パ パ パ) 魂だわ
(Pa pa pa) It's a soul
Welcome さぁ、踊ろうよ This is Halloween Night
Welcome, come on, let's dance. This is Halloween Night.
Party, ikaga deshita deshou ka?
How was the party?
Chanto kochiragawa no oukoku ni modotte korarete imasu ka?
Have you properly returned to the Kingdom on this side?
Meikai no joou-sama ni kiniirarete shimau to,
If the Queen of the Underworld takes a liking to you,
Tamashii wo ubawarete shimatte, kaette koraremasen kara ne.
your soul will be stolen and you won't be able to return.
Modotte korarete, lucky deshita.
You were lucky to make it back.
Nante.
Just kidding.
Kyou no ohanashi wa dou deshita ka?
How were today's stories?
Tanoshikatta deshou ka.
Did you enjoy them?
Watashi ga toku ni okiniiri wa, tantei no ohanashi de shite,
My personal favorite was the detective story,
Konkai okikase dekite totemo ureshikatta desu.
and I was very happy to be able to tell it to you this time.
Sou da. Itsuka anata no ohanashi mo kikasete kudasai ne.
Oh, right. Please let me hear your story someday too.
Moshikasuru to ano hon ni,
Perhaps in that book,
Anata no ohanashi mo kakishirusareru kamo shiremasen yo?
your story might be written down as well, you know?
Nanto ittemo, naka fushigi na hon desu kara.
After all, it is quite a mysterious book.
Nani ga okoru ka, shisho de aru watashi ni mo wakarimasen.
Even I, the librarian, don't know what will happen.
Sate, sorosoro ojikan desu ne.
Well then, it's about time.
Mata ohanashi ga kikitaku narimashitara,
If you ever want to hear a story again,
Itsudemo kono oukoku toshokan e okoshi kudasai.
please come to this Kingdom Library anytime.
Soredewa, sayonara.
Until then, farewell.
Hajimari wa kitto hitotsu no negai
The beginning is surely a single wish
Sore wo daite watashi wa umareta
Embracing that, I was born
Kodoku na yozora furueru yubi de
In the lonely night sky, with trembling fingers
Tentoten wo tsunageyou
Let's connect the dots
Whoa...
Sukun-bu no minasan! Junbi wa dekitemasu ka!
Sukun-bu everyone! Are you ready!
Say-ho-ho! Ikimasu yo!
Say-ho-ho! Here we go!
Sei! Hora sono kao agete
Sei! Come on, lift up your face
Minna de te wo tatakeba
If everyone claps their hands
Sei! Madamada michi no tochuu
Sei! We're still on the way
Sekai wo koeru yo
We'll cross the world
Sei! Hora hoshii mono wa gaman
Sei! Don't hold back on what you want
Tomaranai zenyoku desu kara
Because it's full speed non-stop
Yume wo kakikaetara
If we rewrite the dream
Oikake tsuzukeyou
Let's keep chasing it
Tomoni tsunagu fanfare GO!
The fanfare that connects us together, GO!
Yeah!
Hai! Hai!
Dakara kimi ga itsuka
So if someday you
Jibun jishin no kagayaki wo miushinatta tokini wa
lose sight of your own brilliance
Omoidashite ne bokura no seika wa
remember that our anthem
Kimi ga iru kara kagayaku
shines because you are here
Whoa... La la la...
Oh yeah!
Musuu no hoshi no naka
Among the countless stars
Hikari wo kimi ga kureta
You gave me light
Oh yeah yeah yeah!
Motto!
More!
Koete yukeru sa
We can go beyond
Supernova okose ima
Wake up a supernova, now
Nando datte toberu
We can fly again and again
Kore wa magiremonaku bokura no kiseki
This is unmistakably our miracle
Hi Friends!
Whoa...
Best Friends! Sukon-bu!